Eleanor Dickinson collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Guides to the Collections in the Archive of Folk Culture
Eleanor Dickinson collection 1968-1991
AFC 1970/001
Dickinson, Eleanor, 1931-
manuscripts: 90 folders.
preservation tapes: 99 sound tape reels (261 hrs. 30 min.): analog, 2 track, various speeds; 10 in.
86 sound cassettes: analog.
170 video reels; various sizes.
11 videocassettes; various sizes.
18 photographic prints: black and white; 3 x 5 in.
17 color slides.
222 powerpoint slides: digital prints, grayscale.
2 artifacts.
Archive of Folk Culture, American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
This collection of video recordings, sound recordings, manuscripts, photographs, graphic materials, and artifacts documents Protestant religious revival meetings of various denominations in the southern Appalachian region, primarily in Tennessee, West Virginia, Kentucky, Virginia, and Georgia. The collection includes interviews with church leaders and members of congregations, and documentation of religious services, healing services, revivals, hymn singing, sermons, snake handling, and other religious rites and customs recorded by Eleanor Dickinson from 1968 to 1991. Other topics include beekeeping, church roadside signs, religious quilts, snake hunting, drinking strychnine, decorating graves in cemeteries, church dinners, and more. Included are some religious and secular radio programs recorded by Dickinson, including programs from Nashville, Tennessee, featuring bluegrass music, and a program featuring Paul Simon; and documentation of Protestant revivals in Oakland and San Francisco, California. Dickinson's interviews with visionary artist Rev. Howard Finster on various occasions between August 1, 1981 and July 25, 1991 in Summerville, Georgia, are included in the collection. The collection also includes audio logs and transcripts, video logs, the collector's powerpoint presentations (2004), documentation of Dickinson's exhibition, "Revival!," at the Corcoran Gallery of Art in 1970; and other manuscripts.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Dickinson, Eleanor, 1931-; Finster, Howard, 1916-2001; Finster, Howard, 1916-2001--Interviews.
Subjects
African American churches--Appalachian Region, Southern.; African Americans--Religion.; Baptism in the Holy Spirit--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Baptism in the name of Jesus--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Baptism--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Baptists--California--Oakland.; Baptists--Religious life--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Bee culture--Tennessee.; Cemeteries--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Christian art and symbolism--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Church of God--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Church of God--California--San Francisco.; Church signs--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Clergy--Appalachian Region, Southern--Interviews.; Coal miners--West Virginia--Religious life.; Copperhead--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Easter service.; Easter--California--Oakland.; Evangelicalism--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Evangelistic sermons--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Exorcism--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Field recordings--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Field recordings--California.; Glossolalia--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Healing--Religious aspects--Baptists.; Healing--Religious aspects--Holiness churches.; Healing--Religious aspects--Pentecostal churches.; Holiness churches--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Hymns, English--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Old-time music--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Pentecostal churches--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Pentecostalism--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Pentecostals--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Prayer--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Quilts--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Rattlesnake hunting--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Religious dance--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Revival hymns--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Revivals--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Sermons, American--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Seventh-Day Adventists--California--San Francisco.; Shape-note singing--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Snake cults (Holiness churches)--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Snake hunting--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Stigmatization--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Strychnine--Social aspects--Appalachian Region, Southern.; Witness bearing (Christianity)
Places
Appalachian Region, Southern--Social life and customs.; Knoxville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs.
Form/Genre
Christian radio programs.; Drawings.; Ethnography.; Field recordings.; Interviews.; Photographs.; Prayers.; Radio airchecks.; Sermons.; Sound recordings.; Video recordings.
Arrangement
Organized by accession in fourteen accruals, then organized by format.
Acquisition
Eleanor Dickinson, collector and donor; 1970-2004.
Accruals
See Appendix A for details.
Related Material
Eleanor Dickinson papers, 1951-2003, Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C.
Oral history interview with Eleanor Dickinson, 2000 October 25, Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C.
Access and Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Access to recordings may be restricted. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact.
Scope and Content
This collection of video recordings, sound recordings, manuscripts, photographs, graphic materials, and artifacts documents Protestant religious revival meetings of various denominations in the southern Appalachian region, primarily in Tennessee, West Virginia, Kentucky, Virginia, and Georgia. The collection includes interviews with church leaders and members of congregations, and documentation of religious services, healing services, revivals, hymn singing, sermons, snake handling, and other religious rites and customs recorded by Eleanor Dickinson from 1968 to 1991. Other topics include beekeeping, church roadside signs, religious quilts, snake hunting, drinking strychnine, decorating graves in cemeteries, church dinners, and more. Included are some religious and secular radio programs recorded by Dickinson, including programs from Nashville, Tennessee, featuring bluegrass music, and a program featuring Paul Simon; and documentation of Protestant revivals in Oakland and San Francisco, California. Dickinson's interviews with visionary artist Rev. Howard Finster on various occasions between August 1, 1981 and July 25, 1991 in Summerville, Georgia, are included in the collection. The collection also includes audio logs and transcripts, video logs, the collector's powerpoint presentations (2004), documentation of Dickinson's exhibition, "Revival!," at the Corcoran Gallery of Art in 1970; and other manuscripts.
Container List
- Series I: Manuscripts
  - Subseries A: Administrative files
    - Finding aid (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Administrative materials, 43 pages (estimate) (Box-folder 1/2)
      Acquisitions and processing records from 1969 to 1998. Includes subfolders for miscellaneous materials, plus accruals part 5 through 14.
    - Collection materials (2004 accrual), 9 pages (Box-folder 1/3)
      Photocopies of materials donated by Dickinson in 2004 as part of the collection.
    - Preservation transfer of moving image items, 181 pages (Box-folder 1/4)
      Condition report worksheets from the vendor.
    - Concordances, 61 pages (total) (Box-folder 1/5)
      The documents include the AFC ID numbers for the original items, the collector's ID numbers, ID numbers for the preservation copies, shelflist numbers, and LC item barcodes.
      - Subfolder A: Concordance for sound recordings, 4 pages
      - Subfolder B: Concordance for original moving image items and Betacam copies, 7 pages
      - Subfolder C: Concordance for original moving image items and Digital Betacam copies., 7 pages
    - Correspondence, 1969-1996, 61 pages (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Biographical materials, 19 pages (Box-folder 1/7)
      See folder 1/10 for a photograph of Eleanor Dickinson in the Corcoran Gallery of Art newsletter, Notes, September 1970. See also folders 2/3 and 2/4 for published articles about Eleanor Dickinson.
    - Two lists: "Hymnals Used at Revivals" and "Eleanor Dickinson Collection of Revival Artifacts.", 14 pages (total) (Box-folder 1/8)
      The hymnals were donated to the Music Division, Library of Congress, and the revival artifacts were donated to the Smithsonian Institution by Dickinson.
  - Subseries B: Unpublished writings
    - Dickinson's notes on the collection: "Creekie on Revival Tapes" and "Revival." (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Song texts: "Life is Like a Mountain Railroad" and "We Need a Whole Lot More of Jesus", 1 page (Box-folder 1/10)
    - "An Echo Out of Africa: Unacknowledged Cultural Borrowing of Religious Expression from the Black Slaves in the Great Revival Movement" 1981, 40 pages (Box-folder 1/11)
      An unpublished paper, by Eleanor Creekmore Dickinson.
  - Subseries C: Published materials
    - Newspaper clippings and other promotional materials on "Revival!" (Box-folder 1/12)
    - Two publications, 20 pages. (Box-folder 1/13)
      "Revival at the Corcoran," in Notes, September 1970, and a photocopied catalog from the exhibit "Revival!" by Eleanor Dickinson (1970).
    - Revival! (book), by Eleanor Dickinson and Barbara Benziger, 1974, 180 pages (Box-folder 1/14)
      First edition, published by Harper & Row, autographed by Dickinson.
    - That Old Time Religion: 100 Hymns, Songs, and Stories (book), by Barbara Benziger and Eleanor Dickinson, 1975, 124 pages. (Box-folder 2/1)
    - That Old Time Religion, 1979, 41 pages (Box-folder 2/2)
      A catalog from the 1979 exhibit of the same name; published by the Oakland Museum History Department, and a photocopy of the exhibit poster.
    - "Eleanor Dickinson: Social Historian and Artist," by Helga Epstein, December 1980, 6 pages (Box-folder 2/3)
      Published in American Artist, December 1980, Volume 44, Issue 461, pages 80-83, 95-97.
    - "Confirming the Word: Snake-Handling Sects of Southern Appalachia," by Marsha Maguire, Summer 1981, 21 pages per copy (42 pages total) (Box-folder 2/4)
      Published in The Quarterly Journal of the Library of Congress 38, Summer 1981, pages 166-179. Includes original and photocopy. See folder 4/23 for more photographs of serpent handlers taken by Eleanor Dickinson.
    - Revival! A catalogue from an exhibition on Protestant revivalism, 1981, 36 pages each (72 pages total) (Box-folder 2/5)
      Two copies of the catalog, published by the Tennessee State Museum. See folder 4/24 for images of the exhibition (35 mm color slides).
    - Portfolio, reviews, and resume/bibliography, 7 pages (Box-folder 2/6)
      Miscellaneous excerpts from press reviews of Dickinson exhibits, and Dickinson resume/bibliography.
  - Subseries D: Audio logs and transcripts
    - Audio logs: AFC 1970/001: AFS 14079-14082 (LWO 5781, Reels 1-4), Summer 1968-August 15, 1969 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Audio transcripts: AFC 1970/001: AFS 14079 (LWO 5781, Reel 1A)., 1 page (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Audio transcripts: AFC 1970/001: AFS 14079 (LWO 5781, Reel 1A-1B), 15 pages (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Audio transcripts: AFC 1970/001: AFS 14079-14,081 (LWO 5781, Reels 1B-3A), 46 pages (Box-folder 2/10)
    - Audio transcripts: AFC 1970/001: AFS 14081 (LWO 5781, Reel 3A-3B), 6 pages (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Audio transcripts: AFC 1970/001: AFS 14082 (LWO 5781, Reel 4A-4B), 24 pages (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Audio logs: AFC 1970/001: AFS 15455-15458 (LWO 7152, Reels 1-4), July 31-August 6, 1972, 9 pages (Box-folder 2/13)
    - Audio transcripts: AFC 1970/001: AFS 15455 (LWO 7152, Reel 1A)., 6 pages (Box-folder 2/14)
    - Audio transcripts: AFC 1970/001: AFS 15455 (LWO 7152, Reel 1B), 3 pages (Box-folder 2/15)
    - Audio transcripts: AFC 1970/001: AFS 15456-15457 (LWO 7152, Reels 2B-3A), 47 pages (Box-folder 2/16)
    - Audio logs: AFC 1970/001: AFS 15661-15666 (LWO 7468, Reels 1-6), June 21-July 1, 1973, 6 pages (Box-folder 2/17)
    - Audio transcripts: AFC 1970/001: AFS 15661 (LWO 7468, Reel 1)., 14 pages (Box-folder 2/18)
    - Audio transcripts: AFC 1970/001: AFS 15662 (LWO 7468, Reel 2A), 13 pages (Box-folder 2/19)
    - Audio transcripts: AFC 1970/001: AFS 15662-15663 (LWO 7468, Reels 2B-3A), 8 pages (Box-folder 2/20)
    - Audio transcripts: AFC 1970/001: AFS 15663 (LWO 7468, Reel 3B), 7 pages (Box-folder 2/21)
    - Audio transcripts: AFC 1970/001: AFS 15664 (LWO 7468, Reel 4A), 18 pages (Box-folder 2/22)
    - Audio transcripts: AFC 1970/001: AFS 15664 (LWO 7468, Reel 4B), 71 pages (Box-folder 2/23)
    - Audio transcripts: AFC 1970/001: AFS 15665 (LWO 7468, Reel 5A), 40 pages (Box-folder 2/24)
    - Audio transcripts: AFC 1970/001: AFS 15665-15666 (LWO 7468, Reels 5B-6A), 3 pages (Box-folder 2/25)
    - Audio logs: AFC 1970/001: AFS 19133-19145 (LWO 9619, Reels 1-13), April 3, 1975-July 13, 1976, 12 pages (Box-folder 2/26)
    - Audio logs: AFC 1970/001: AFS 19283-19288 (LWO 12249, Reels 1-6), June 12-July 16, 1977, 14 pages (Box-folder 3/1)
      Photocopies of handwritten notes on the original 13 tape boxes (two copies).
    - Audio logs: AFC 1970/001: AFS 20267-20307 (LWO 16506, Reels 1-41), July 15, 1977-July 2, 1978, 50 pages (Box-folder 3/2)
      Photocopies of handwritten notes on the original 58 tape boxes (some boxes photocopied out of order). No photocopies for the following original Dickinson numbers: D5, D8, D11, D14, D17, D20, D22, D23, and D25-D27. D44 has a corner torn from the photocopy, with some information loss.
    - Audio logs: AFC 1970/001: AFS 23158-23176 (RWA 8361-8379), August 8, 1980 to December 1, 1981, 26 pages (Box-folder 3/3)
      Photocopies of handwritten notes on the original 32 tapes and tape boxes.
    - Audio logs and description: AFC 1970/001: AFS 23177-23182 (RWA 7817-7822), July 1976 to August 5, 1976, 88 pages (Box-folder 3/4)
      Photocopies of handwritten notes on the original 8 audiocassette tape boxes and photocopies of handwritten notes on the original 6 audio reels, dubbed from moving images in the collection (two copies).
    - Audio logs: SR001-006, Old Harp singing and revivals, October 1976-August 31, 1981, 27 pages (Box-folder 3/5)
      Photocopies of handwritten notes from the original 6 audiocassette tape housing materials and one accompanying slip of paper (two copies).
    - Audio logs: AFC 1970/001: SR007-017, serpent handling churches, September 5-9, 1981, 46 pages (Box-folder 3/6)
      Photocopies of handwritten notes from the original 11 audiocassette tape housing materials (two copies).
    - Audio logs: AFC 1970/001: SR018-031, July 4, 1980 to August 24, 1982, 19 pages (Box-folder 3/7)
      Photocopies of handwritten notes from original 14 audiocassette tape housing materials.
    - Audio logs: AFC 1970/001: SR032-041, April 3-August 14, 1983, 15 pages (Box-folder 3/8)
      Photocopies of handwritten notes from original 10 audiocassette tape housing materials.
    - Audio logs: AFC 1970/001: SR042-060, July 7-26, 1984, 26 pages (Box-folder 3/9)
      Photocopies of handwritten notes from original 19 audiocassette tape housing materials.
    - Audio logs: AFC 1970/001: SR061-086: "Howard Finster tapes," August 1, 1981-July 25, 1991, 93 pages (Box-folder 3/10)
      Photocopies of handwritten notes from original 25 audiocassette tape housing materials (two copies).
    - Transcripts, interviews: "1962 Brother Harrison Mayes," and "Tape Interview B and ECD", 13 pages (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Transcripts, interviews: "Creekie and Bob Weems (not Miles) interview Powell about B. Mayes", circa 1968-1969, 35 pages (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Audio transcript of the sermon: "When God Takes Census," June 7, 1970, 26 pages (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Transcripts, 8 pages (Box-folder 3/14)
  - Subseries E: Video logs and transcripts
    Logs were not created for all video materials.
    - Video logs: AFC 1970/001: MV001-030 (V-76-A-1 to V-76-O-1), July 1976-August 5, 1976 (Box-folder 3/15)
      See folder 4/11 for photocopies of tape boxes and inserts.
    - Video logs: AFC 1970/001: MV031-051 (V-77-A-1 to V-77-M-1), July 2-22, 1977, 22 pages (Box-folder 3/16)
      See folder 4/12 for photocopies of tape boxes and inserts.
    - Video logs: AFC 1970/001: MV052-091 (V-78-A-1 to V-78-N-3), April 2-July 11, 1978, 49 pages (Box-folder 3/17)
      See folder 4/13 for photocopies of tape boxes and inserts.
    - Video logs: AFC 1970/001: MV092-112 (V-79-A-1 to V-79-K-1), March 11-August 8, 1979, 20 pages (Box-folder 3/18)
      See folder 4/14 for photocopies of tape boxes and inserts.
    - Video logs: AFC 1970/001: MV115-133, AFC 1970/001: MV148-151 (V-80-A-1 to V-80-S-1), June 29-August 16, 1980, 64 pages (Box-folder 4/1)
      See folder 4/15 for photocopies of tape boxes and inserts.
    - Transcripts and notes: Tent Revival, Madison, Tennessee, 1980. AFC 1970/001: MV134-147 (V-80-L-4 to V-80-L-7), August 1-2, 1980, 13 pages (Box-folder 4/2)
      See folder 4/16 for photocopies of tape boxes and inserts.
    - Video logs: AFC 1970/001: MV152-165 (V-81-A to V-81-J), June 1981 to October 23, 1981, 18 pages (Box-folder 4/3)
      See folder 4/17 for photocopies of tape boxes and inserts.
    - Video logs: AFC 1970/001: MV170-171 (V-82-A-1 to V-82-A-2), April 11, 1982, 2 pages (Box-folder 4/4)
      See folder 4/19 for photocopies of tape boxes and inserts.
    - Video logs: "Revival!" AFC 1970/001: MV175-179 (VC-81-A to VC-81-F), 1979-1981, 15 pages (Box-folder 4/5)
      See folder 4/21 for photocopies of tape boxes and inserts.
    - Video log, AFC 1970/001: MV180: "Howard Finster From God Paints a Picture," July 19, 1985, 1 page (Box-folder 4/6)
      See folder 4/22 for photocopies of tape boxes and inserts.
    - Video logs and transcripts, AFC 1970/001: MV181: "Real Time in West Virginia with Four Holiness People, 1978" (recorded June 24, 1978), and "Jean Schilling and Lee Shilling, Creekmore Cabin, Elkmont, Tennessee," (recorded August 23, 1987), June 24, 1978; August 23, 1987, 16 pages (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Transcript: The Today Show (television broadcast), October 28, 1970, 3 pages (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Video logs and notes: "Southern Appalachian Video Tapes, 1978," 1978, 4 pages (Box-folder 4/9)
    - Notes on edited tape: "Brother Harrison Mayes, Kentucky," by Eleanor Dickinson, 1980, 2 pages (Box-folder 4/10)
  - Subseries F: Original reel boxes and inserts (photocopies)
    - AFC 1970/001: MV001-030 (V-76-A-1 to V-76-O-1), 1976 (Box-folder 4/11)
    - AFC 1970/001: MV031-051 (V-77-A-1 to V-77-M-1), 1977, 16 pages (Box-folder 4/12)
      See folder 3/16 for video logs.
    - AFC 1970/001: MV052-091 (V-78-A-1 to V-78-N-3), 1978, 41 pages (Box-folder 4/13)
      See folder 3/17 for video logs.
    - AFC 1970/001: MV092-114 (V-79-A-1 to V-79-K-1), 1979, 32 pages (Box-folder 4/14)
      See folder 3/18 for video logs.
    - AFC 1970/001: MV115-133, MV148-151 (V-80-A-1 to V-80-S-1), 1980, 35 pages (Box-folder 4/15)
      See folder 4/1 for video logs.
    - AFC 1970/001: MV134-137 (V-80-L-4 to V-80-L-7), 1980, 8 pages (Box-folder 4/16)
      See folder 4/2 for video logs.
    - AFC 1970/001: MV152-165 (V-81-A-1 to V-81-J), 1981, 26 pages (Box-folder 4/17)
      See folder 4/3 for video logs.
    - AFC 1970/001: MV166-169, 1981, 5 pages (Box-folder 4/18)
      No Dickinson numbers.
    - AFC 1970/001: MV170-171 (V-82-A-1 to V-82-A-2), 1982, 5 pages (Box-folder 4/19)
      See folder 4/4 for video logs.
    - AFC 1970/001: MV174, 1983, 2 pages (Box-folder 4/20)
    - AFC 1970/001: MV175-179 (VC-81-A to VC-81-F), 1981, 2 pages (Box-folder 4/21)
    - AFC 1970/001: MV180-181, 1987, 3 pages (Box-folder 4/22)
      No Dickinson numbers. See folders 4/5 and 4/6 for video log.
  - Subseries G: 2004 accrual
    - Personal Bible: Verses of Comfort, Assurance, Salvation (Box-folder 4/23)
    - "Revival" (PowerPoint presentation) (Box-folder 4/24)
      Grayscale printouts of color images from the presentation. See Box 5 for CF2, containing original digital files for these images.
    - "Elkmont" (PowerPoint presentation) (Box-folder 4/25)
      Grayscale printouts of color images from the presentation (see Box 5 for CF3, containing original digital files for these images).
    - Manuscripts used for "Revival!" (Box-folder 4/26)
      4 Rally Day postcards. Heavy-stock paper; color; the largest measuring 3 inches by 5 inches. "A Light to Lighten the Gentiles the Glory of Israel." Paper clipping, measuring 2 inches by 3 inches; color.
    - Rally Day card, 3 inches by 5 inches; color. (Box-folder 4/27)
      Heavy-stock paper; color; 3 inches by 5 inches. This item is not part of the "Revival!" group of materials.
    - Prayer card with the Lord's Prayer and the Ten Commandments, 2 inches by 3 inches; color (Box-folder 4/28)
      Identified on the label as Victorian; probably printed circa 1905-1911.
- Series II: Sound recordings
  - AFC 1970/001: AFS 14079-14082, 1968-1969, 4 sound tape reels (13.5 hours): analog, 3.75 ips, 2 track
  - AFC 1970/001: AFS 15455-15458, Summer 1972, 4 sound tape reels (16 hours): analog, 3.75 ips, 2 track
    Revival church services, including snake-handling services, in Tennessee, Kentucky, and West Virginia.
  - AFC 1970/001: AFS 15661-15666, June-July 1973, 6 sound tape reels (24 hours): analog, 3.75 ips, 2 track
    Revival church and tent services in Tennessee and West Virginia.
  - AFC 1970/001: AFS 19133-19145, July 13, 1976, 13 sound tape reels (26 hours): analog, 7.5 ips, 2 track
    Tent revival meetings and other religious observances including: hymns, sermons, testifying, glossolalia, and snake handling; interview with folk artist and preacher Brother H.H. Mayes.
  - AFC 1970/001: AFS 19283-19288, June-July 1977, 6 sound tape reels (12 hours): analog, 7.5 ips, 2 track
    Pentecostal religious services (both Anglo and African American) recorded in the Appalachian coal country of West Virginia and Tennessee involving hymns, sermons and such practices as glossolalia, faith healing, and snake handling.
  - AFC 1970/001: AFS 20267-20307, July 15, 1977-August 12, 1979, 41 sound tape reels (82 hours): analog, 7.5 ips, 2 track
    Tent revivals, church services, creek baptisms, and interviews in Virginia, West Virginia, Kentucky and Tennessee. Includes snake-handling, preaching, praying, singing, and testifying.
  - AFC 1970/001: AFS 23158-23176, August 8, 1980-December 1, 1981, 19 sound tape reels (76 hours): analog, 3.75 ips, 2 track
    Includes homecomings, interviews, music, prayer meetings, public confessions, radio broadcasts, religious services, snake handling, snake hunts, tent revivals, and testimonies.
  - AFC 1970/001: AFS 23177-23182, July 1976-August 5, 1976, 6 sound tape reels (12 hours): analog, 7.5 ips, 2 track
    Audio portion of 5-inch open-reel videos documenting faith healing, foot washing, glossolalia, music, road signs, snake handling, services, tent revivals, and testimonies; also includes interviews with beekeeper Lem Owenby.
  - AFC 1970/001: SR001, October 1976, 1 sound cassette; 60 min.
    Demonstration of Sacred Harp method and style of hymn singing (shape notes sung before verses with words). Singers in First Baptist Church, Wears Valley, Tennessee. Probably the same church and singers in tapes SR001-SR004 (Accrual part 13: "Old Harp Singers"). No original ID number.
  - AFC 1970/001: SR002, October 1976, 1 sound cassette; 60 min.
    Hymn singing and conversation; singers in Cades Cove Baptist Church, Wears Valley, Tennessee. Accrual part 13, "Old Harp Singing." No original ID number.
  - AFC 1970/001: SR003, September 1, 1978, 1 sound cassette; 60 min.